{"name": "61D  2005-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. A fingernail grows at an average rate of 0.12 inches per month. Rip Van Winkle, a character in a story by Washington Irving, slept for 20 years. If his fingernails grew at the average rate, approximately how many inches did each grow while he slept?", "choices": {"A": "28.8", "B": "24.0", "C": "20.0", "D": "12.0", "E": "2.4"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. In the figure below, \u2220A \u2245 \u2220D, \u2220B \u2245 \u2220E, and \u25b3ABC \u2245 \u25b3DEF. The measure of \u2220A is 20\u00b0. The mea-sure of \u2220F is 75\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220B ?", "choices": {"A": "20\u00b0", "B": "75\u00b0", "C": "85\u00b0", "D": "95\u00b0", "E": "105\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Shanika has a bag containing 50 pieces of candy: 6 strawberry, 12 orange, 10 lime, and 22 lemon. If Shanika randomly takes a piece of candy from the bag, what is the probability that the piece she takes is strawberry or lime?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. It is estimated that each 4-ounce portion of a certain type of apple contains 60 calories. What is the estimate for the number of calories contained in a 15-ounce portion of this type of apple?", "choices": {"A": " 15", "B": " 16", "C": " 60", "D": " 225", "E": " 240"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. Dan and Kyla dined at a restaurant, and their bill was $29.74. They would like to leave a tip of approximately 15% of their bill. Which of the following is closest to this amount?", "choices": {"A": "$1.50", "B": "$3.00", "C": "$3.78", "D": "$4.00", "E": "$4.50"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. Buyer's Buddy Supermarket is running a sale on all 4 flavors of 2-liter Zing-N-Zest soft drinks. The sale price for each 2-liter bottle is $0.59, with a limit of 6 bottles per flavor. At most, how many 2-liter bottles can be purchased for $12.89, excluding tax?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "10", "C": "21", "D": "22", "E": "24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. According to the U.S. Energy Information Administration, in 1989 the U.S. population consumed a total. of 81,342 trillion British thermal units (Btu) of energy, including 5,677 trillion Btu of nuclear electric power and 2,884 trillion Btu of hydroelectric power. In scientific notation, how many more Btu of nuclear electric power were consumed than Btu of hydroelectric power?(Note: 1 trillion = 1,000,000,000,000)", "choices": {"A": "2.457 \u00d7 1015", "B": "2.793 \u00d7 1015", "C": "5.250 \u00d7 1015", "D": "7.567 \u00d7 1015", "E": "7.846 \u00d7 1015"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. When 3x - 12y = 6 and y = -2, what is the value of x ?", "choices": {"A": "-18", "B": "-6", "C": "", "D": "4", "E": "10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Diastolic blood pressure tends to increase linearly with age. Suppose that the average diastolic blood pressure of 20-year-olds is 120 and the average diastolic blood pressure of 60-year-olds is 140. Given this model, what would be the average diastolic blood pressure of 50-year-olds?", "choices": {"A": "120", "B": "125", "C": "130", "D": "135", "E": "140"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. The expression (2x + 3)(3x - 2) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "5x + 1", "B": "5x - 1", "C": "6x2 - 6", "D": "6x2 - 5x - 6", "E": "6x2 + 5x - 6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Jan returned a library book that was 9 days, overdue.The library charged Jan s cents per day for the first6 overdue days and 20 cents per day for each overdue day after 6 overdue days. Which of the following is an expression for the total amount, in cents, Jan was charged?", "choices": {"A": "s + 180", "B": "6s + 20", "C": "6s + 60", "D": "9s + 20", "E": "9s + 60"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. What is the value of h(1.5) when h(x) = -4x2 + 20x + 32 ?", "choices": {"A": "26", "B": "50", "C": "53", "D": "56", "E": "71"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. What is the area, in square inches, of \u25b3ABC below?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "12", "C": "14", "D": "24", "E": "48"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. For what value of x is 3(x + 5) = 2(x -6) true?", "choices": {"A": "27", "B": "11", "C": "-11", "D": "-21", "E": "-27"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Which of the following is equivalent to ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "7a", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  Suppose that w, y, and z each stand for a digit from 0 through 9 and    5w7+  92y  1,z96What is the value of the product w \u00b7 y \u00b7 z ?", "choices": {"A": "19", "B": "28", "C": "216", "D": "252", "E": "270"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  In \u25b3ABC, \u2220B is a right angle and the measure of \u2220A is 36\u00b0. A second right triangle, \u25b3DEF, is being constructed so that \u2220E is a right angle and the measure of \u2220D is double the measure of \u2220A. What is the measure of\u2220F ?", "choices": {"A": "72\u00b0", "B": "54\u00b0", "C": "30\u00b0", "D": "27\u00b0", "E": "18\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  The figure below shows a circle with a radius of 5 cm and a chord of the circle. The chord is 3 cm from the center of the circle. What is the length, in centimeters, of the chord?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "8", "E": "10"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. What is the sum of the 2 solutions of the equation x2 + 3x - 28 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "-28", "B": "-7", "C": "-3", "D": "0", "E": "4"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. The time, t seconds, required for a simple pendulum x feet long to make 1 complete swing can be modeled by. How many seconds are required for 1 complete swing of a simple pendulum that is 8 feet long?", "choices": {"A": "Less than 1", "B": "Between 1 and 2", "C": "Between 2 and 3", "D": "Between 3 and 4", "E": " More than 4"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. What is the value of y in the solution to the following system of equations ?2x + y + 3 = 30x + 2y = 30", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "8", "C": "11", "D": "17.4", "E": "29"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. In the right triangle below, the side lengths given are in inches: Which of the following expressions equals the sine of \u2220R ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  A regular pentagon, P1, has a perimeter of 25 inches, while another regular pentagon, P2, has a perimeter that is 15 inches greater than the perimeter of P1. The length of each side of P2 exceeds the length of each.side of P1 by how many inches?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "5", "C": "8", "D": "10", "E": "15"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. A certain type of combination lock has 3 dials: the first2 dials each have settings for all the digits 0 through 9, and the third has settings for all the 26 capital letters of the alphabet. A combination consists of one setting from each of the dials. (For example, 6-4-P is a combination. ) How many different combinations are possible? ", "choices": {"A": "260", "B": "520", "C": "1,664", "D": "2,600", "E": "5,200"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Through how many degrees does a wheel rotate in 1.5 minutes at 45 revolutions per minute? ", "choices": {"A": "24,300", "B": "16,200", "C": "12,150", "D": "8,100", "E": "4,050"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. What is the fourth term in the geometric sequence 36, -12, 4, \u2026 ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "-1", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  [(a3)2(a2)]3 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "a10", "B": "a11", "C": "a21", "D": "a24", "E": "a36"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Joe wants to put a border all the way around his bedroom walls 1 inch below the ceiling, as shown below. The border is sold only in whole rolls, and each roll is 5 yards long. Joe's bedroom is rectangular, 12 feet wide and 14 feet long. What is the minimum number of rolls of border Joe must buy?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. What is the area, in square coordinate units, of the parallelogram with vertices as shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "18", "C": "24", "D": "30", "E": "36"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Suppose that the measure of the larger of 2 supplementary angles is 5 times the measure of the smaller angle. What is the measure of the larger angle?(Note: In the figure below, \u2220ABD and \u2220DBC are supplementary. The sum of their measures is 180\u00b0.)", "choices": {"A": "30\u00b0", "B": "36\u00b0", "C": " \u00b0", "D": "\u00b0", "E": "150\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line with the equation 3x - 2y = 24 ? ", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "3", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. The community orchestra will give 18 performances this season. A season ticket costs $60, and single-performance tickets cost $5 each. Huong purchased a season ticket. What is the minimum number of performances Huong must attend to save money by buying the season ticket instead of buying single-performance tickets for the performances she attends\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "11", "D": "12", "E": "13"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  A line in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane passes through the origin and the point (-12, 6). An equation of this line is:", "choices": {"A": "y = -x - 6", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "y = x + 18", "E": "y = 2x"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Which of the following lists the real values of x that make the expression undefined?", "choices": {"A": "0 only", "B": "3 only", "C": "-1, 3 only", "D": "1, -3 only", "E": "0, 1, -3 only"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. How many positive prime factors does the number 30 have?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. What is the distance, in coordinate  units, between the points (-4, 8) and (2, 2) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. The measures of the interior angles of a trapezoid are in the ratio of 3:4:5:6. What is the measure of the largest interior angle?", "choices": {"A": "10\u00b0", "B": "20\u00b0", "C": "60\u00b0", "D": "120\u00b0", "E": "180\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Which of the following ratios is equivalent to the ratio of 22 to 44?", "choices": {"A": "1 to 2", "B": "1 to 4", "C": "1 to 8", "D": "1 to 16", "E": "1 to 64"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. Use the following information to answer questions 39-41.Ms. Mart\u00edn uses a computer program to produce periodic progress reports for the 10 students in her Advanced Mathematics \u2161 class. The report gives a student's scores on tests, quizzes, and homework assignments and the average of all 10 students' scores on each. The progress report shown below was produced near the end of the term for Richard Baldwin.The solution of which of the following inequalities would tell Richard the minimum score (represented by x) he needs to earn on Quiz #4 in order to have a quiz.average of at least 90?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Use the following information to answer questions 39-41.Ms. Mart\u00edn uses a computer program to produce periodic progress reports for the 10 students in her Advanced Mathematics \u2161 class. The report gives a student's scores on tests, quizzes, and homework assignments and the average of all 10 students' scores on each. The progress report shown below was produced near the end of the term for Richard Baldwin.When Richard took the posttest, his score was 78. The increase from his pretest score to his posttest score was what whole percent of his pretest score?", "choices": {"A": "88%", "B": "87%", "C": "74%", "D": "13%", "E": "12%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. Use the following information to answer questions 39-41.Ms. Mart\u00edn uses a computer program to produce periodic progress reports for the 10 students in her Advanced Mathematics \u2161 class. The report gives a student's scores on tests, quizzes, and homework assignments and the average of all 10 students' scores on each. The progress report shown below was produced near the end of the term for Richard Baldwin.In Ms. Mart\u00edn's class, each student who does not turn in a homework assignment, receives a score of 0 for the assignment. Of the 10 students in Ms. Mart\u00edn's Advanced Mathematics II class, what is the maximum possible number who did not turn in Homework #1 ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Which of the following could be the last 2 digits of an integer that is a perfect square?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "23", "C": "56", "D": "87", "E": "99"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. Which of the following gives the fractions , ,andin order from least to greatest?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. What is the midpoint of the line segment with endpoints (3, 6) and (10, -24) in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "(5, -12)", "D": "", "E": "(13, -18)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A circle in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane has center (3, 8) and is tangent to the x-axis. The point (x, y) is on the circle if and only if x and y satisfy which of the following equations?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 3)2 + (y - 8)2 = 64", "B": "(x - 3)2 + (y - 8)2 = 9", "C": "(x + 3)2 + (y - 8)2 = 64", "D": "(x + 3)2 + (y + 8)2 = 9", "E": "(x + 3)2 + (y + 8)2 = 8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. The circle in the figure below has a radius of 8 centimeters. What is the length, in centimeters, of the arc that is intercepted by a central angle of 60\u00b0?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "4\u03c0", "D": "8\u03c0", "E": "10\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. If 27 \u00b7 3x = 9y - 6 and y = 6, then what is the real number value of x ? ", "choices": {"A": "-3", "B": "-2", "C": "-1", "D": "0", "E": "3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. The diagram below shows a quarter of each of 2 circles both having point C as their center. Point B lies on AC and point D lies on CE. The length of BC is 5 inches and the length of AB is 3 inches. What is the area, in square inches, of the shaded portion?", "choices": {"A": "4\u03c0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "16\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. From a blimp 1,130 feet above the ground, the angle of depression to a marker on the ground is 52\u00b0, as shown in the figure below. Which of the following expressions gives the distance along the ground, in feet, from the marker to point P directly below the blimp?", "choices": {"A": "1,130 tan 38\u00b0", "B": "1,130 sin 38\u00b0", "C": "1,130 cos 38\u00b0", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Given a real number n such that |n| &gt; n, which of the following must be true?", "choices": {"A": "n \uff1c 0", "B": "n = 0", "C": "n = -n", "D": "n \uff1e | -n |", "E": "\\sqrt{n}\">"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. For all figures in which point O is the intersection of AD and BC, and m\u2220CDO &gt; m\u2220BAD (the measure of \u2220CDO is greater than the measure of \u2220BAD), such as the figure shown below, which of the following statements is always FALSE?", "choices": {"A": "AB || CD", "B": "AB \u2245 CD", "C": "AD \u22a5 BC", "D": "m\u2220BCD &gt; m\u2220BAD", "E": "\u2220AOB &gt; \u2220COD"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. The variables a, b, and c are all integers and a + b + c = 50. If a &lt; 0 and 0 &lt; b &lt; 30, then the minimum possible value for c is:", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "17", "C": "21", "D": "22", "E": "25"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A polynomial function P(x) has degree n. The graph in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane of y = P(x) contains exactly 3 points on the x-axis. Which of the following could NOT be the value of n?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "5", "C": "4", "D": "3", "E": "2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The radius of a right circular cone is doubled and its height is tripled to form a new right circular cone. What is the ratio of the volume of the original cone to the volume of the new cone?(Note:  for radius r and height h.\uff09", "choices": {"A": "1:6", "B": "1:12", "C": "1:18", "D": "1:36", "E": "1:216"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Two integer values of x solve the equation x2 - x = b. One of these is positive, and the other is negative. Which of the following could be the value of b ?", "choices": {"A": "-20", "B": "-1", "C": "0", "D": "9", "E": "12"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. Which of the following integers must be a factor of the sum of any 3 consecutive positive integers?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  A solid block of wood has 6 rectangular faces. The.length, width, and height of the block are a, b, and.c inches, respectively. Which of the following expressions represents the block's surface area, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "6abc", "B": "4ab + 2bc", "C": "(a + b + c)2", "D": "2a + 2b + 2c", "E": "2(ab + ac + bc)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  The quadrants of the standard (x, y) coordinate plane are shown in the figure below. Given that the vertex of \u2220\u03b1 is the origin, the positive x-axis is one side of \u2220\u03b1, its other side lies in Quadrant II, and , what is cos 2\u03b1?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. For a specific nonzero value of b, the graph of y = sin bx in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane intersects the x-axis at k values of x in the interval 0 \u2264 x \uff1c 2\u03c0. At how many values of x in this interval does the graph of y = 2 sin bx intersect the x-axis?", "choices": {"A": "k", "B": "k - 2", "C": "k + 2", "D": "", "E": "2k"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60.  In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, the coordinates of D are (d, k), and the coordinates of E are (e, k). When D is rotated 180\u00b0 about E, the result is F. In terms of d, e, and k, what are the coordinates of F?", "choices": {"A": "(e + d, 2k)", "B": "(e - d, 0)", "C": "(e - d, k)", "D": "(2e - d, k)", "E": "(2d - e, k)"}, "correct": "D"}]}